Hello I'm Sifu Mallon with the Clearwater Kung Fu Center.
This is my assistant Melissa and this Kickboxing.
Starting with our punching.
The punches, okay, we're going to be using, okay, our kickboxing punches.
So we have several different punches we'll cover.
The first set is going to be our Straight Jab, meaning if I have my left foot in front, I'm using my left hand, okay and throwing a straight punch in front of the body.
I have Melissa demonstrate this slow so I can point out some of the finer details of it.
So she begins from her stance, both feet point the same general direction.
Good.
Our hands are up in our high guard position.
So elbows are loose, shoulders are relax, right, and chin dips forward slightly.
Now from here, she's going to advance forward with her left foot and throw a left jab out.
Hold it there a few hold after you throw it out.
Okay, now if we're looking straight on to the target, we want to actually bring our punch, okay, so that it's inside your shoulder range.
So if you look at the body as a triangle this way, we're pointing, punching toward the center of the body.
The forward leg, if you're looking, right, the foot is flat and the weight is on the inside of the foot, not allowing the weight go to the outside so that you're lifting your toe, you're unstable at that point.
So weight on the inside.
If we're not punching anything especially in beginning phases, we want to maintain your elbow, okay, in neutral.
This means we're not going to lock the elbow out when we throw the punch.
Okay.
This is going to be straight but not lock.
So this is lock and that's what we want, a little relax.
Bring the hand back in.
"And Melissa go ahead and fire off a few repetitions of the jab.
Good.
So this technique is called our Straight Jab, Kickboxing.